Shiva Srinivasan

Sr QA Engineer

Methodical Senior QA Engineer, mentor and author experienced in software development processes and optimal testing strategies. Helps teams produce exceptional products by offering in-depth quality assurance support. Open and clear communicator with good multitasking skills, organized nature and strong attention to detail. Expert Cypress and Selenium user.

Work History

2021-01 -Current

Principal Quality Assurance Engineer

CrowdStreet, Portland, OR

- Reduced regression execution runtime by 40 minutes by integrating tests with Cypress dashboard to aid smart parallelization and orchestration
- Work closely with Engineering leaders and architects to develop testing strategies for greenfield features.
- Document coding standards for automation framework
- Mentor QA engineers on automation techniques and testing procedures
- Establish performance testing suite from ground up and set up CI/CD process for it
- Increase test coverage to over 90%
- Constantly monitor testing suite to identify and address test flakiness
- Produced and maintained technical documentation for project reference

2020-01 -2020-12

Senior Quality Assurance Engineer

CrowdStreet, Portland, OR

- Replaced existing codeless automation with new Cypress based CI/CD framework which reduces test execution time from 5hrs to 35 minutes and save over \$2500 annually
- Mentored engineering team on writing scalable and maintainable tests

Contact

Address

Beaverton, OR, 97008

Phone

720-233-2416

E-mail

sivkumar.s@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/sivkumars

Technical Skills

Jira

Excellent

C#

Very Good

SQL

Very Good

Selenium

Very Good

Cypress

Excellent

Git

••••• Excellent

Team City



 Increased technical documentation to improve onboarding efficiency

- Proposed development and testing improvements to positively impact usability, function and performance and aid early feedback.
- Assessed current process and propose path for continuous improvement that align with organization's goals

2015-06 - Sr QA Engineer 2019-12

Navex Global Inc, Portland, OR

- Designed and implemented selenium based automation framework
- Instilled culture of Quality in organization
- Introduced process improvements that aided early feedback from customers
- Mentored new QA engineers and provide support
- Was subject matter expert for all identity and access management related queries

2009-01 - Application Developer/Conversion Lead 2013-01

CenturyLink, Vancouver, WA

- Built performance optimization solutions reducing operation costs by over 50% with \$120K annual savings
- Designed real time reporting tools to track conversion timelines and accuracy
- Spearheaded multiple development projects post conversion driving continuous improvement to processes, systems, work flow and customer responsiveness

2005-01 - Application Developer 2009-01

Qwest, Denver, CO

- Recruited to develop and maintain mission critical application
- Responsible to deliver solutions that meet business objectives ensuring adherence to change management processes Key contributions
- Implemented process improvements and designed automated solutions increasing service levels and stability

Very Good

Jenkins



AWS



Javascript



Node.js



React



Expertise

Domain Knowledge



Strategic planning



CI/CD Implementation



Automation knowledge



Training and mentoring



Team Leadership



- Provided CPU reduction solutions on multiple legacy applications saving over \$500k annually
- Reduced application downtime by optimizing cycle times on nightly batch activities

Education

2000-01 - Bachelor Degree: Electronics and Communication Engineering

Barathiyar University - Coimbatore, India

Accomplishments

- Setup functional automation and performance frameworks from the ground up in multiple organizations
- Significantly decrease regression suite execution times to aid faster feedback and releases
- Performance optimization that resulted in savings of over \$500k annually